<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Ernaud Breissie Blog : Looking For Gamedesign</title><link href="https://ernaud-breissie.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ernaud-breissie.github.io/blog/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://ernaud-breissie.github.io/blog/</id><updated>2024-01-27T09:20:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Auction with freeloader</title><link href="https://ernaud-breissie.github.io/blog/auction-with-freeloader.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-27T09:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-01-27T09:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ernaud Breissie</name></author><id>tag:ernaud-breissie.github.io,2024-01-27:/blog/auction-with-freeloader.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this auction mechanic, there are 6 players (P1, P2, etc.). When player P1 plays an auction card, each player has the choice to bet coins. Each player has two gold coins and two brass coins. The card specifies the following rewards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a total of 6 gold coins is …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this auction mechanic, there are 6 players (P1, P2, etc.). When player P1 plays an auction card, each player has the choice to bet coins. Each player has two gold coins and two brass coins. The card specifies the following rewards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a total of 6 gold coins is bet in the auction bag, each player receives 1 additional gold coin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If 5 gold coins are bet (but not 6), players P3, P4, and P5 each receive 2 gold coins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If less than 5 gold coins are bet, all players lose 1 gold coin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mechanic is inspired by the "free rider" concept where some players can benefit without contributing, but if too many players adopt this strategy, everyone is penalized, including the "free riders".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;version française :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans cette mécanique d'enchère, il y a 6 joueurs (J1, J2, etc.). Lorsque le joueur J1 joue une carte d'enchère, chaque joueur a le choix de miser des pièces. Chaque joueur possède deux pièces d'or et deux pièces de laiton. La carte spécifie les récompenses suivantes :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Si un total de 6 pièces d'or est misé dans le sac d'enchère, chaque joueur reçoit 1 pièce d'or supplémentaire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Si 5 pièces d'or sont misées (mais pas 6), les joueurs J3, J4 et J5 reçoivent chacun 2 pièces d'or.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Si moins de 5 pièces d'or sont misées, tous les joueurs perdent 1 pièce d'or.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cette mécanique s'inspire du concept du "passager clandestin" où certains joueurs peuvent tirer profit sans contribuer, mais si trop de joueurs adoptent cette stratégie, tout le monde est pénalisé, y compris les "passagers clandestins".&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Gamedesign"></category><category term="mecanique"></category><category term="mechanism"></category><category term="gamedesign"></category><category term="auction"></category><category term="enchere"></category></entry><entry><title>Team but not Team victory</title><link href="https://ernaud-breissie.github.io/blog/team-but-not-team-victory.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-26T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-01-26T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ernaud Breissie</name></author><id>tag:ernaud-breissie.github.io,2024-01-26:/blog/team-but-not-team-victory.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An interesting game design concept which  involves two teams : Each player secretly receives information about which team they are on, but does not know the teams of the other players. Victory is determined individually. To win, a player must avoid being in the same team as the player who is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An interesting game design concept which  involves two teams : Each player secretly receives information about which team they are on, but does not know the teams of the other players. Victory is determined individually. To win, a player must avoid being in the same team as the player who is in the last position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version française :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un concept de game design intéressant qui implique deux équipes : Chaque joueur reçoit secrètement l'information indiquant dans quelle équipe il se trouve, mais ne connaît pas les équipes des autres joueurs. La victoire est déterminée individuellement. Pour gagner, un joueur doit éviter d'être dans la même équipe que le joueur qui se trouve en dernière position.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Gamedesign"></category><category term="mecanique"></category><category term="mechanism"></category><category term="gamedesign"></category><category term="victory"></category></entry><entry><title>Contact</title><link href="https://ernaud-breissie.github.io/blog/contact.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2001-01-01T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2001-01-01T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ernaud Breissie</name></author><id>tag:ernaud-breissie.github.io,2001-01-01:/blog/contact.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you want to contact me please drop me a mail &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:ernaudbreissie[@AT]gmail.com"&gt;ernaudbreissie[@AT]gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version française :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;si vous voulez me contacter envoyez moi un email :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:ernaudbreissie[@AT]gmail.com"&gt;ernaudbreissie[@AT]gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Contact"></category><category term="contact"></category></entry></feed>